[柯克]舰长日志：星历5818.4
[KIRK] Captain's Log : Star date 5818.4.
企业号当前工作的银河系象限中
A botanical plague is devastating a planet
一个星球正被一场瘟疫毁灭
in the quadrant of the galaxy where the Enterprise is operating at present.
它危及整个星球上的植被
It threatens to destroy the vegetation on the entire planet,
让它无法居住
leaving it uninhabitable.
根据联邦命令，我们正以最高曲速驶向阿尔达纳星球
At Federation orders, we're proceeding at top warp speed to the planet Ardana,
那里存在唯一已知的天顶石来源
where the only known source of zenite exists.
它是可以阻止瘟疫的一种物质
It is the one substance that can halt the plague.
舰长，阿尔达纳的高级顾问已准备好在斯特拉托斯接待您，长官
Captain, the high adviser of Ardana is ready to receive you on Stratos, sir.
在斯特拉托斯？那是他们的云城，对吗，史波克先生？
On Stratos? That's their cloud city, isn't it, Mr. Spock?
是的，舰长
It is, Captain.
一定有什么误会
There must be some mistake.
你有矿井入口的坐标吗？
Do you have the coordinates to the mine entrance available?
已提供给传送人员
They've been provided to the transport officer,
以及高级顾问会议厅的坐标
along with those of the council chamber of the high adviser.
柯克呼叫传送室
Kirk to transporter room.
[斯科特]准备传送
[SCOTT] Ready to transport.
斯科特先生，你锁定的是矿井入口还是他们的云城斯特拉托斯？
Mr. Scott, are you locked in on the mine entrance or on their cloud city, Stratos?
矿井入口，是你要求的，舰长
The mine entrance. That's what you ordered, Captain.
好的，乌乎拉，告诉高级顾问
Right. Uhura, tell the high adviser that
由于紧急情况，我们要求取消欢迎仪式
we request to dispense with the welcoming ceremonies due to the emergency,
我们将直接传送到矿井入口
that we're beaming directly down to the mine entrance
以确保尽快交付天顶石，需求十分迫切
in order to ensure the fastest possible delivery of the zenite : the need is urgent.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
史波克先生，跟我来
Mr. Spock, come with me.
告诉他们我们感到很荣幸
Oh, and tell them that we appreciate the honor
我们期待将来的访问
and that we look forward to some visit in the future.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
斯特拉托斯，舰长，一座真正漂浮在空中的城市
Stratos, Captain, a city actually floating in the sky.
[柯克]看起来和它的名声一样平静
[Kirk] Looks as tranquil as its reputation.
它是银河系中最有趣的大都市之一
It is one of the most interesting metropolises in the galaxy.
你来过这儿吗，舰长？
Have you ever visited here, Captain?
来过一次，但没能有时间游览
Once. I didn't have time to look around.
我没有机会，然而，我听说它的艺术形式是无与伦比的
I've never had the opportunity. However, I hear its art forms are incomparable.
是的，艺术是人们的主要职业
Yes, art is the population's chief occupation.
这是一个完全知识分子的社会
It is a totally intellectual society.
所有形式的暴力都已被消除
All forms of violence have been eliminated.
那里是矿井入口
There's the mine entrance.
天顶石应该在那里
The zenite consignment should have been there.
I don't understand it.
我不明白
当我们传送下来时，特罗格莱特矿工们应该已经交货了
Those Troglyte miners were supposed to have made delivery when we beamed down.
也许有别的入口，舰长
Perhaps there is another entrance, Captain.
看来特罗格莱特已经改变了他们对交付的看法
It would seem the Troglytes have changed their minds about delivery.
[柯克]宇宙，最后的边疆
[KIRK] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission, to explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第二十一集
云端看守者
The Cloud Minders
你们是谁？为什么要攻击？
Who are you? What's the meaning of this attack?
干预导致的攻击，舰长，来吧
Interference breeds attack, Captain. Come on!
经你们政府议会的许可，我们来这里执行紧急任务
We're here by permission of your government council on an emergency mission.
继续前进，舰长
Move on, Captain.
特罗格莱特，停下！
Troglytes, halt!
投降，否则我们会开火！
Surrender or we'll fire!
你们受伤了吗，先生们？
Are you harmed, gentlemen?
不，只是受到了一点惊吓
No, just a little shaken up.
我是普拉苏斯，星球议会的高级顾问
I'm Plasus, high advisor of the planet council.
我是企业号的柯克舰长，这是我的大副史波克先生
Captain Kirk, Enterprise. Mr. Spock.
您好，顾问先生
Greetings, Mr. Advisor.
我对你在阿尔达纳受到的不愉快的欢迎深表歉意
My regrets for the unpleasantness of your welcome to Ardana.
它相当热血
It was rather warm.
很不幸，特罗格莱特关于使用暴力
Unfortunately, violence is habitual with the Troglytes.
但我向你保证，这种侮辱不会逍遥法外
But I assure you, this insult will not go unpunished.
我更关心天顶石交付
I'm more concerned with the zenite consignment.
为什么不在指定位置？
Why wasn't it in its specified location?
显然，破坏者没收了它，我就知道他们会这么做
Apparently, the Disrupters have confiscated it, just as I knew they would.
破坏者？他们是谁？
The Disruptors? Who are they?
一小群特罗格莱特不满者
A small group of Troglyte malcontents.
所有其他特罗格莱特都受他们控制
All the other Troglytes are completely dominated by them.
破坏者要为拒绝继续开采天顶石负责
It's the Disrupters who are responsible for their refusal to continue mining for zenite.
他们同意交付，你的议会向我们保证过
They agreed to the delivery. Your council assured us of it.
他们的同意显然是个诡计，为了获得有价值的人质
They agreed obviously as a ruse to get valuable hostages.
人质？出于什么目的？
Hostages? For what purpose?
迫使议会满足他们的要求
To force the council to meet their demands.
立即组织搜索小队并找到天顶石货物
Organize a search party immediately and find the zenite consignment.
同时，舰长，我建议你和大副史波克
Meanwhile, Captain, I would suggest that you and First Officer Spock
来我们斯特拉托斯做客
be our guests on Stratos.
很好，我希望搜索尽快完成，顾问先生
Very well. I do hope the search will be brief, Mr. Advisor.
我们将尽一切努力，来吧，先生们
We'll do everything possible to make it so. Come, gentlemen.
非同凡响
Remarkable.
我见过的持续反重力上升的最佳案例
The finest example of sustained anti-gravity elevation I've seen.
哨兵告诉我有贵客，父亲
The sentinel told me of our honored guests, my father.
我是来问候的
I came to extend greetings.
非常有礼貌
A most gracious act.
先生们，我们星球上最无与伦比的艺术作品之一
Gentlemen, one of our planet's most incomparable works of art.
我的女儿卓克辛
My daughter Droxine.
詹姆斯·柯克舰长
Captain James Kirk.
很荣幸，女士
Pleasure, madam.
@确实，是的，舰长
Indeed, yes, Captain.
以及大副史波克
And First Officer Spock.
我以前从未见过瓦肯人，先生
I have never before met a Vulcan, sir.
我也不是艺术品，女士
Nor I a work of art, madam.
来吧，先生们，我们的城市有很多值得看的
Come, gentlemen. There is much to see in our city.
这是我们的议会画廊，它对所有城市居民开放
This is our council gallery. It is open to all city dwellers.
我们把各种艺术形式中最优秀一些汇集在这里
We have some of the finest of our various art forms assembled here
以供观看和思考…
for the viewing and contemplation of every
又是破坏者！
Disruptors again!
真可怕！他们正在掠夺整个城市
How dreadful! They're despoiling the whole city!
掠夺？出于什么目的？
Despoil? For what purpose?
通过让我们陷入持续混乱
By keeping us in constant turmoil,
他们希望迫使议会接受他们的要求
they hope to force the council to accede to their demands.
他们的诉求是什么？
What are their demands?
完全不合理，舰长
Completely unreasonable, Captain,
但无需你担心
but nothing you need be concerned with.
我必须要关心，如果它影响到向天璇二运送天顶石的话
I must concern myself with it if it should interfere with the delivery of zenite to Merak II.
顾问先生，植物生命是那个星球上氧气的唯一来源
Mr. Advisor, the plant life is the source of oxygen on that planet.
显然，如果所有植物生命都被摧毁
Obviously, if all plant life is destroyed,
类人生命也将随之消失
the humanoid life will follow.
我向你们保证，先生们，你们会如愿以偿
I assure you, gentlemen, you will get what you came for.
但愿如此，阿尔达纳是联邦成员
I hope so. Ardana is a member of the Federation.
而你们的议会有责任确保没有东西
And it is your council's responsibility that nothing interferes
干扰其对联邦其他成员的义务
with its obligation to another member of the Federation.
当然，我们承担责任
Of course, and we accept the responsibility.
他们为什么要破坏艺术？
Why do they destroy art forms?
那是大家的损失
That is a loss to everyone.
艺术对破坏者来说毫无意义
Art means nothing to the Disruptors.
这是他们理解的唯一形式
This is the only form they understand.
你们的到来引起的骚乱令人疲倦
The disturbances accompanying your arrival have been most wearying.
毫无疑问你们需要休息
No doubt you would like to rest. -
那再好不过了
That would be most welcome.
卧室已为你们准备好
Chambers have been prepared for you.
哨兵会带你们去
A sentinel will guide you to them.
我很难过他们第一次访问我们星球就受到了如此恶劣的对待
I'm sorry they were so poorly treated on their first visit to our planet.
幸好他们没有受重伤
It's fortunate they were not seriously hurt.
哦，是的，要是那样就太尴尬了
Oh, yes, that would have been dreadful.
进一步的暴力可能会在阿尔达纳和联邦之间创造极大的困难
Further violence could create grave difficulties between Ardana and the Federation.
破坏者们一定是疯了才会攻击两个这样迷人的陌生人
The Disruptors must be mad to attack two such charming strangers.
他们每天都变得更加勇敢和坚定
They grow more daring and determined every day.
现在他们谋求在银河系中寻找盟友
Now they seek to find allies in the galaxy.
你认为柯克舰长和他非常有魅力的大副
Do you think that Captain Kirk and his very attractive officer
会觉得我们要为他们的受伤负责吗？
will feel that we're responsible for their injuries?
我还一直以为你担心我们的外交关系
All this time I thought you were worried about our diplomatic relations.
抱歉，顾问，但是这个特罗格莱特被抓到离开城市
Apologies, Mr. Advisor, but this Troglyte was apprehended leaving the city.
他没有通行证，所以我想你会想要审问他
He is without a transport card so we thought you would want to question him.
取下他的面罩
Remove his shields.
你在斯特拉托斯是干什么的，特罗格莱特？
What is your business in Stratos, Troglyte?
说！我命令你
Speak! I command you.
我的工作是修理
My business is to repair.
修理什么？
Repair what?
有损坏的入口面板
There are damaged entrance panels.
的确
Indeed.
那么你一定有维修许可证
Then you must have a repair permit.
在哪里？
Where is it?
忘了
It was forgotten.
你是不是也忘了你的通行证？
Did you also forget your transport card?
你的哨兵攻击我时弄丢了
It was lost when your sentinels attacked me.
你的洞穴工具丢在哪里了？
And where was your cavern implement lost?
有没有可能是这个？
Could this perhaps be it?
我是来修理的
I came to make repairs.
你可以修理
And you shall make them,
告诉我们破坏者的名字
by giving us the names of the Disruptors.
我什么都不知道
I know nothing.
我建议你多了解一下
I would advise you to increase your knowledge.
这对于特罗格莱特来说是不可能的
That is not possible for a Troglyte.
斯特拉托斯城的居民已经说过了
The Stratos city dwellers have said it.
把他固定在讲台上
Secure him to the rostrum.
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
多么的不幸
How unfortunate.
多么的不幸啊
[思考]这是一个反差非常强烈的动荡的星球
[THINKING] This troubled planet is a place of the most violent contrasts.
那些接受回报的人
Those who receive the rewards
与那些肩负重担的人是完全分开的
are totally separated from those who shoulder the burdens.
这不是一个明智的领导
It is not a wise leadership.
在斯特拉托斯上，一切都是无与伦比的美丽和愉悦
Here on Stratos, everything is incomparably beautiful and pleasant.
高级顾问的迷人女儿，卓克辛，尤其如此
The high advisor's charming daughter, Droxine, particularly so.
卓克辛这个名字听起来很适合她
The name Droxine seems appropriate for her.
我想知道，她是否能保持如此纯洁和甜蜜的心灵
I wonder, can she retain such purity and sweetness of mind
并意识到星球表面人们的生活？
and be aware of the life of the people on the surface of the planet?
在那里，矿井的严酷生活正在给人们灌输一种痛苦的仇恨
There, the harsh life in the mines, is instilling the people with a bitter hatred.
当我们传送下来时领导袭击我们的年轻女孩
The young girl who led the attack against us when we beamed down
充满了绝望的暴力
was filled with the violence of desperation.
如果可爱的卓克辛认识到年轻矿工的痛苦
If the lovely Droxine knew of the young miners' misery,
我想知道这些知识会如何影响她
I wonder how the knowledge would affect her.
史波克先生，我以为你陪柯克舰长去了休息室
Mr. Spock! I thought you had accompanied Captain Kirk to the rest chamber.
你的动静叫醒了我
Your movements awakened me.
我很抱歉
My apologies.
我没有意识到会打扰你
I did not realize they would disturb you.
这噪音只有瓦肯人的耳朵能听到
Only Vulcan ears would find the noise discernible.
看起来瓦肯人在很多方面都非常不同
It seems that Vulcans are fascinatingly different, in many ways.
斯特拉托斯的居民也是如此
The same may be said of Stratos' inhabitants.
瓦肯人的眼睛也很挑剔
Vulcan eyes are very discerning, too.
我听说，智力上
I hear that, intellectually,
瓦肯人与斯特拉托斯的城市居民一样高度进化
Vulcans are as highly evolved as Stratos city dwellers.
我们确实为自己的逻辑感到自豪
We do pride ourselves on our logic.
又是你！
You again!
你睡得很浅，舰长
You sleep lightly, Captain.
是的，责任是个好老师
Yes, duty is a good teacher.
我看你换了裁缝
I see you've changed your dressmaker.
放开我
Release me.
让你再次攻击我吗？那将是愚蠢的
So you can attack me again? That would be foolish.
如果你害怕，就叫警卫，舰长
Call the guards if you're afraid, Captain.
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
事实上，我觉得这很有趣
In fact, I find this rather enjoyable.
我不觉得！
I do not!
好，我跟你做个交易
All right, I'll make a deal with you.
你回答几个问题，我就让你起来
You answer some questions and I'll let you up.
什么问题？
What questions?
你先保证
Your word first.
我会回答
I will answer.
你每七年才交配一次吗？
You only take a mate once every seven years?
七年的周期是所有瓦肯人的固有生物学特征
The seven-year cycle is biologically inherent in all Vulcans.
在那个时候，交配超过了所有其他的动机
At that time, the mating drive outweighs all other motivations.
史波克先生，没有什么能扰乱这个周期吗？
And is there nothing that can disturb that cycle, Mr. Spock?
极致的女性美…
Extreme feminine beauty.
…总是令人不安，女士
.is always disturbing, madam.
[柯克]史波克？
[KIRK] Spock?
我不是来杀你的，舰长
I did not come here to kill you, Captain.
那这是为什么？
Then why this?
挟持你
To take you hostage.
我打扰你了吗，舰长？
Am I intruding, Captain?
万娜
Vanna.
卓克辛
Droxine.
你为什么来这里？
Why have you come here?
欢迎我们的客人，就像我在你父亲家里服侍时
To welcome our guests, as I was taught to do
被教导的那样
when I served in your father's household.
她伤到你了吗，舰长？
Has she injured you, Captain?
哦，不，完全没有
Oh, no, not at all.
事实上，她的来访很有启发性
In fact, her visit was quite enlightening.
哦？
Oh?
是的，似乎特罗格莱特以为企业号是来恐吓他们的
Yes, it seems the Troglytes are under the impression that the Enterprise is here to intimidate them.
立刻派哨兵来休息室
Send a sentinel to the rest chamber immediately.
不是以为，舰长，是事实
It is not impression, Captain. It is the truth.
我们来这里是为了得到天顶石货物，就是这样
We're here to get that zenite consignment, and that's it.
星舰不运输货物
Starships do not transport cargo.
在紧急情况下，他们会做任何事情
In times of emergency, they will do anything.
而且相信我，这场植物瘟疫就是紧急情况
And believe me, this botanical plague is an emergency.
谎言不会让特罗格莱特留在洞穴中，你的星舰也不会
Lies will not keep the Troglytes in caverns and neither will your starship.
你说话像个破坏者，万娜
You talk like a Disruptor, Vanna.
我为我的人民说话
I speak for my people.
他们与斯特拉托斯的居民一样有进入云城的权利
They have as much right to the clouds as the Stratos dwellers.
斯特拉托斯是给顾问和学者的
The Stratos is for advisors and studiers.
特罗格莱特在这里做什么？
What would Troglytes do here?
居住，在阳光和温暖中
Live. In the sunlight and warmth,
每个人都应该这样
as everyone should.
洞穴很温暖，你们的眼睛不习惯光线
The caverns are warm and your eyes are not accustomed to light.
就像你的头脑不习惯逻辑一样
Just as your minds are not accustomed to logic.
不习惯光线和温暖？
Unaccustomed to light and warmth?
这对所有类人生物来说都是必要的
That's necessary to all humanoids.
当然，你不会向特罗格莱特否认这一点
Surely you don't deny it to Troglytes.
特罗格莱特是工人，舰长
The Troglytes are workers, Captain.
你当然知道这一点
Surely you must be aware of that.
他们从土里开采天顶石并运输
They mine zenite for shipment, till the soil.
那些事情在这里没法做
Those things cannot be done here.
换句话说，他们干了维持斯特拉托斯所需的所有体力活
In other words, they perform all the physical toil necessary to maintain Stratos.
这就是他们在我们社会中的作用
That is their function in our society.
但不允许他们分享它的好处
But they are not allowed to share its advantages.
他们怎么能分享他们不理解的东西？
How can they share what they do not understand?
可以教他们理解
They can be taught to understand.
尤其是在一个以启蒙为荣的社会中
Especially in a society that prides itself in enlightenment.
劳逸完全分离
The complete separation of toil and leisure
给了阿尔达纳这个完美平衡的社会系统，舰长
has given Ardana this perfectly balanced social system, Captain.
我们为什么要改变它？
Why should we change it?
星球的表面几乎无法忍受
The surface of the planet is almost unendurable.
将一部分人口限制在这样的困境中
To restrict a segment of the population to such hardship
在进化的文化中是无法想象的
is unthinkable in an evolved culture.
表面被暴力破坏
The surface is marred by violence.
就像特罗格莱特一样
Like the Troglytes.
在斯特拉托斯，我们已经完全消除了暴力
Here on Stratos, we have completely eliminated violence.
你拒绝透露其他破坏者的名字？
You still refuse to disclose the names of the other Disrupters.
没有破坏者
There are no Disruptors.
很好，如果你喜欢光线…
Very well. If you prefer the rays.
[史波克]特罗格莱特是一个古代地球术语的缩写，舰长
[SPOCK] Troglyte is an abbreviation of an ancient Earth term, Captain.
它的字面意思是穴居者
Its technical translation is cave dweller.
是的，我早应该意识到的
Yes. I should have realized.
[尖叫]
[SCREAM]
顾问先生！
Mr. Advisor!
你说你要质问万娜，而不是折磨她
You said you were going to question Vanna, not torture her.
她很固执
She's stubborn.
而且正如你自己所指出的，舰长
And as you yourself pointed out, Captain,
对你的天顶石货物的搜索必须很短
the search for your zenite consignment must be short.
当然还有比这更好的方法
Surely there are better methods than this.
身体不适是极其有说服力的，舰长
Physical discomfort is extremely persuasive, Captain.
是的，但我不会在有人被折磨的时候袖手旁观
Yes, but I won't stand by while someone is tortured.
放过万娜让整个星球被毁灭更可取？
Is it preferable to spare Vanna and allow an entire planet to be destroyed?
现实中的暴力与理论大相径庭，不是吗，女士？
Violence in reality is quite different from theory, is it not, madam?
但他们还能理解什么，史波克先生？
But what else can they understand, Mr. Spock?
所有你我都理解并期待的生活小事
All the little things you and I understand and expect from life,
比如平等、善良、正义
such as equality, kindness, justice.
特罗格莱特不像斯特拉托斯居民，史波克先生
Troglytes are not like Stratos dwellers, Mr. Spock.
它们是劣等物种的聚​​合体
They're a conglomerate of inferior species.
知识社会的抽象概念
The abstract concepts of an intellectual society
超出了他们的理解范围
are beyond their comprehension.
对万娜来说，忠诚和领导力的抽象概念似乎很清楚
The abstract concepts of loyalty and leadership seem clear to Vanna.
一些特罗格莱特作为仆人被带来这里
A few Troglytes are retainers.
万娜是其中之一，所有的哨兵都是
Vanna was one, as all the sentinels.
他们比其他人接受了更多的培训
They've received more training than the others.
但显然没有更多的报酬
But obviously no more consideration.
我看不出这种持续批评的目的
I fail to see the purpose of this continued criticism.
下次再用那个东西，不是在你身上就是在我身上
The only way you'll use that device again is on one of us.
[轻笑]原始英勇的壮观展示，先生们
[CHUCKLES] An imposing display of primitive gallantry, gentlemen.
你知道哨兵可以把你带走吗？
You realize the sentinels could remove you?
当然
Of course,
但星际舰队指挥部不会接受对其指挥人员
but starfleet command won't take kindly to having either rays or physical force
使用射线或武力的做法，顾问先生
used against one of its command personnel, Mr. Advisor.
你为什么这么关心这个破坏者的安危？
Why are you so concerned with this Disruptor's well-being?
除了纯粹的人道主义之外，我的命令是拿到天顶石
Beyond plain humanitarianism, my orders are to get that zenite!
那就别插手，我会帮你你弄到的
Then stop interfering, and I'll get it for you.
你用酷刑弄不到！
You won't get it through torture!
我们会给你弄到的，用我们自己的方法！
We will get it for you, and in our own way!
将犯人转移到禁闭室
Remove the prisoner to confinement quarters.
您将立即返回您的船
You will return to your ship at once
否则我将亲自联系星际舰队指挥部
or I shall contact your Starfleet command myself
并报告你对本星球政府的干涉
and report your interference with this planet's government.
[通讯器哔哔声]
[Communicator Beeps On]
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
[斯科特]企业号，舰长
[SCOTT] Enterprise, Captain.
斯科特先生，我们准备传送上去了
Mr. Scott, we're ready to beam up.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
如果柯克舰长再次出现，杀了他
If Captain Kirk appears again, kill him.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5819.0
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate 5819.0.
距天顶石货物消失已经超过8个小时了
More than 8 hours have passed since the consignment of zenite disappeared
我们仍然没有发现它的踪迹
and we have still found no trace of it.
我们从天璇二那里得知植物瘟疫正在迅速蔓延
We received word from Merak II that the botanical  plague is spreading rapidly.
必须在12小时内交付天顶石
Delivery of the zenite is imperative within 12 hours
否则星球上的所有生命将被毁灭
or all life on the planet will be annihilated.
乌乎拉上尉，通知星际舰队指挥部天顶石尚未交付
Lieutenant Uhura, advise Starfleet command that the zenite has not been delivered.
在我看来，普拉苏斯完成交付的方法不会成功
In my opinion, Plasus' method of accomplishing delivery will not succeed.
如果天顶石没有很快交付
If the zenite is not delivered shortly,
我将不得不违反普拉苏斯的不干涉命令
I shall have to violate Plasus' order of noninterference
并用理智赢得特罗格莱特领导者的信任
and win the confidence of the Troglyte leader with the use of reason.
这可能并不容易，吉姆
That may not be easy, Jim.
医学分析表明特罗格莱特在智力上是低等的
Medical analysis indicates Troglytes are mentally inferior.
那不可能，老骨头
That's impossible, Bones.
特罗格莱特接受了个人牺牲，共同事业
Troglytes have accepted personal sacrifice, a common cause.
低等智力生物做不到这一点
Mentally inferior beings aren't capable of that.
听着，我彻底检查了我的发现
Look, I've checked my findings thoroughly.
他们的智力评级比平均水平低近20%
Their intellect ratings are almost 20% below average.
他们都是同一个种族
They're all the same species.
住在斯特拉托斯上的和住在下面的人
Those who live on Stratos and those who live below
都起源于这个星球
all originated on the planet.
他们的身体智力进化一定是相似的
Their physical and mental evolution must be similar.
这是基本的生物规律
That is basic biological law.
没错，史波克
That's true, Spock.
但显然住在斯特拉托斯上的人的祖先
But obviously the ancestors of those who live on Stratos
从矿井环境中搬了出来
removed themselves from the environment of the mines.
因此，他们避免了某些自然生长的影响
Therefore they avoided the effects of certain natural growths.
自然生长？哪一种？
Natural growths? What kind?
我有这个从地表发来的天顶石样本
I had this zenite sample sent up from the surface.
未密封，它会对这里所有人产生有害影响
Now, unsealed, it would have had detrimental effects on everybody here.
不可思议！天顶石被运往整个银河系
Incredible! zenite is shipped all over the galaxy
任何有植物细菌危险的地方
wherever there's danger of plant bacteria.
没有报告有副作用
No side effects have been reported.
提纯后就没有了
There are none after it's refined.
但在未经加工的状态下
But in its raw state,
它会散发出一种无味、看不见的气体
it emits an odourless, invisible gas
这会阻碍大脑智力功能并增强情绪
that retards the intellectual functioning of the mind and heightens the emotional.
因此，它会释放出剧烈的反应
Therefore, it releases a violent reaction.
矿井里充满了这种气体
And the mines are full of that gas.
对，特罗格莱特经常暴露在它之下
Right. And Troglytes are constantly exposed to it.
老骨头，破坏者，万娜，似乎不可能
Bones, the Disruptors, Vanna. It seems impossible.
几个月来，他们已经智胜了一种高度组织的科学文化
They've outwitted a highly organized, scientific culture for months.
作为斯特拉托斯的一部分，万娜长期避免了暴露
As part of Stratos, Vanna was removed from exposure for a long period.
如果没有曝光，效果就会慢慢消失
It is likely that without such exposure, the effect slowly wears off.
没错，史波克
That's right.
其他破坏者也可能已避免了暴露
The other Disrupters were probably removed from exposure too.
大脑恢复正常了吗？
Does the brain return to normal?
根据发现，应该会
According to findings, it should.
你能中和气体吗？
Can you neutralize the gas?
不，但过滤面罩有效
No, but a filter mask should remove the exposure.
找一个，和我们在传送室碰头
Find one. Meet us in the transporter room.
这种面具能自动消除所有对类人生命有伤害的物质
This mask automatically eliminates all substance injurious to humanoid life
包括化学物质和细菌
chemical as well as bacterial.
我们经常使用过滤面具来…
We've used filter masks frequently on.
你真的希望我相信那面具
And do you really expect me to believe that that mask
可以为特罗格莱特带来智力平等吗？
can achieve intellectual equality for the Troglytes?
有各种迹象表明，这种气体的影响是暂时的
There's every indication that the effect of the gas is temporary,
即使是在反复接触之后
even after repeated exposure.
仅靠一个过滤器怎么能完成
How can a mere filter accomplish
几个世纪进化所没能做到的事情呢？
what centuries of evolution have failed to do?
麦考伊医生彻底分析了天顶石
Dr. McCoy has analyzed the zenite thoroughly.
我们用电脑检查了他的发现
We've checked his findings through the computer.
结果是有效的
And they're absolutely valid.
你的计算机是否解释了我的祖先如何
Do your computers explain how my ancestors,
他们也曾住在洞穴中
who also dwelt in caverns,
进化到足以建立斯特拉托斯
evolved sufficiently to erect Stratos,
而特罗格莱特却没有？
while the Troglytes did not?
不平等的进化
Unequal evolution did not begin
直到你的祖先避免持续暴露在气体中才开始，顾问先生
until after your ancestors removed themselves from constant exposure to the gas, Mr. Advisor.
啊，荒谬！
Ah, preposterous!
现在没时间争论发现了
There's no time to argue about the findings now.
我只是提议告诉万娜这一切
I simply propose to tell Vanna all about them.
我怀疑即使是万娜也不会相信这种无稽之谈
I doubt whether even Vanna will believe such nonsense!
这种无稽之谈可能对特罗格莱特意义重大
This nonsense might mean a great deal to the Troglytes.
我想向他们提供这些过滤面具，以换取天顶石货物
I would like to offer them a supply of these filter masks in exchange for the zenite consignment.
对不起，舰长
I'm sorry, Captain.
这样的提议只会在他们中间引起更多的不安
Such an offer could only cause more unrest among them.
在我们的科学家核查发现之前，我不允许
I cannot allow it until our scientists have checked the findings.
那可能要花几天时间
That could take days.
你是怕口罩有用吗？
Are you afraid the masks will work?
所以你不想让特罗格莱特试试
Is that why you don't want the Troglytes to try them?
你来这里是为了完成紧急任务
You are here to complete an emergency mission,
而不是进行测试，舰长
not conduct tests, Captain.
我是来拿天顶石的！
I'm here to get zenite!
如果这些能帮我们拿到，那我就会用
If these will help me get them, I'll use them.
而我禁止！
And I forbid it!
你的联邦命令没有赋予你
Your Federation orders do not entitle you
挑战地方政府的权利
to defy local governments.
这次通讯到此结束
This communication has ended.
我的外交手段有些不足
My diplomacy is somewhat inadequate.
哦，克服偏见是相当困难的
Oh, it's pretty hard to overcome prejudice.
没有给我们太多选择，不是吗？
Doesn't give us much choice, does it?
也没有时间
Nor time.
我们有10小时40分钟把那批货物运送到天璇二
We have 1 0 hours and 40 minutes to deliver that consignment to Merak ll.
把我送到万娜的禁闭室
Beam me down to Vanna's confinement quarters.
你是说你要违反政府命令返回斯特拉托斯？
You mean you're going back to Stratos against government orders?
如果万娜没有为她的人民获得明确的好处
If Vanna doesn't have something definite to gain for her people,
她宁愿死，也不愿交出那批天顶石货物
she'll die rather than turn over that zenite consignment.
这是唯一能说服她的东西
This is the only thing that might convince her.
舰长
Captain.
如果你被逮到
If you are apprehended
故意违反高级顾问的命令
deliberately violating the high advisor's orders,
如果他愿意，他将有权处决你
he will be within his rights to have you executed, if he chooses.
如果你是在暗示由你来联系万娜
If you're about to suggest that you contact Vanna,
回答是否定的，史波克
the answer's no, Spock.
你也是，老骨头
That goes for you too, Bones.
我想指出的是大副
I'll point out that a first officer is more expendable
比医生或舰长更值得牺牲
than either a doctor or a captain.
官方来说，是的。但这个任务是完全非官方的
Officially, yes. But this mission is strictly unofficial.
没人会参与其中或为其负责，除了我自己
Nobody's to have any part in it, any responsibility for it, but myself.
这是命令，史波克
That's an order, Spock.
你来掌舵
You have the conn.
待命，等我联系你
Stand by till I contact you.
[机器哔哔声，蜂鸣]
[Machine Beeps, Beaming]
瓦娜…
Vanna.
我给你带了一个礼物
I've brought you a gift.
矿井里有危险气体
There's a dangerous gas in the mines
会影响暴露在其中一段时间的特罗格莱特的发育
that affects the development of the Troglytes exposed to it for a period of time.
这个面具将防止进一步的伤害
This mask will prevent any further damage.
来自天顶石的气体？
Gas from zenite?
是的
Yes.
很难相信看不见摸不着的东西会造成这么大的伤害
It's hard to believe something neither seen nor felt can do so much harm.
没错，但想法也是看不见摸不着的
That's true. But an idea can't be seen or felt.
它让特罗格莱特被困在矿井里好几个世纪
That's what's kept the Troglytes in the mines all these centuries.
一个错误的想法
A mistaken idea.
所有特罗格莱特都会戴这些面具吗？
Would all the Troglytes wear these masks?
是的，我会确保联邦工程师制造它们
Yes. I'll see to it that Federation engineers construct them.
要是普拉苏斯不同意？
Suppose Plasus does not agree?
普拉苏斯不是整个政府
Plasus is not the whole government.
确实如此
That is true,
但市议会不会听取特罗格莱特的意见
but the city council will not listen to Troglytes.
一旦天顶石被送到天璇二
As soon as the zenite is delivered to Merak II,
我就会回来
I'll come back.
我会请求为特罗格莱特进行调解的许可，万娜
I'll request permission to mediate for the Troglytes. Vanna.
你必须相信我
You must trust me.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
几个世纪前
Centuries ago,
建造斯特拉托斯的领导们保证
Stratos was built by leaders that gave their word
所有居民都将住在那里
that all inhabitants would live there.
特罗格莱特仍在等待
The Troglytes are still waiting.
天顶石可在数小时内交付
The zenite can be delivered in hours.
现在你不会等太久
You won't have long to wait now.
几个小时可能是几个世纪
Hours can be centuries.
就像承诺可能是谎言一样
Just as words can be lies.
万娜…
Vanna.
你必须相信我
you must trust me.
如果你不这样做，数百万人将死去，一整个星球！
If you don't, millions of people will die. A whole planet!
天顶石是唯一能拯救他们的东西
Zenite is all that can save them.
过滤面具是唯一能拯救特罗格莱特的东西
The filter mask is all that can save the Troglytes.
相信我
Trust me.
拜托
Please.
好吧，舰长
Very well, Captain.
我会相信你
I will trust you.
这批货物位于矿井深处
The consignment lies deep in the mines
只有特罗格莱特知道的地方
in a place known only to Troglytes.
我不能告诉你怎么走
I cannot direct you.
我必须带你去那里
I must take you there.
你要求我的信任，舰长
You asked for my trust, Captain.
你不愿意给我你的吗？
Are you unwilling to give yours?
是给我送茶点的哨兵
It's the sentinel with my refreshment.
等待，我们需要一张通行证才能离开这座城市
Wait. We'll need a transport pass to leave the city.
米德罗
Midro.
万娜
Vanna.
安卡
Anka. -
你回来了
You have returned.
而且我还带了一个人质，抓住他！
And I've brought with me a hostage. Seize him!
我们说好的，你为什么反悔？
We had a bargain. Why did you break it?
你真的以为我会信任你吗，舰长？
Did you really think I would trust you, Captain?
我没那么傻
I'm not such a fool.
我信了你
I trusted you.
你以为你能用你的长篇大论骗过我
You thought you would trick me with your talk
说什么过滤器和看不见的气体来欺骗我
of your filter and your unseen gas.
我比普拉苏斯更不相信你
I don't believe you any more than Plasus.
那你就是个傻瓜
Then you are a fool.
正如我所说，这些面具能解放你们
These masks will free you, as I said.
我们的武器就是我们的自由
Our weapons are our freedom
你刚刚给我提供了两个非常有价值的东西
and you've just furnished me with two very valuable ones.
你和这个
Yourself and this.
抓我对你没有帮助
Holding me won't help you.
我的人还是会来找天顶石货物
My men will still come for that zenite consignment.
没有你的通讯器
Without your communicator,
很难定位到你
you will be hard to locate.
他们还是会来的
They'll still come.
也许吧
Perhaps.
同时，体验一下我们的生活方式，舰长
In the meantime, a taste of our existence, Captain.
像特罗格莱特一样挖掘
Dig as the Troglytes do.
像特罗格莱特一样
As the Troglytes do.
没有那个面具，我…
Without that mask, I haven't.
用你的双手，舰长
With your bare hands, Captain.
[史波克]舰长日志补充，星历5819.3
[SPOCK] Captain's log supplemental, stardate 5819.3.
副驾驶史波克报告
First Officer Spock reporting.
柯克舰长传送到斯特拉托斯
Captain Kirk beamed down to Stratos
试图赢得叛军特罗格莱特的信任
to attempt to win the confidence of the rebel Troglytes.
除非他从斯特拉托斯逃到了矿井
Unless he has made his escape from Stratos to the mines,
否则他的生命受到高级顾问的威胁
his life is in danger from the high advisor.
舰长没有通知我们他的进展
The captain has not informed us of his progress.
就我们而言，我们必须保持沉默
For our part, we must maintain silence.
在不危及他生命的情况下，我们不能帮助他
We can be of no help to him without jeopardizing his life.
你挖得不错，舰长
You dig well, Captain.
看不见的气体似乎没有伤害你
The unseen gas doesn't seem to be harming you.
需要一段时间才能注意到它的效果
It takes a while for its effects to be noticed.
尽管如此，你不需要这个
Nevertheless, you won't need this.
安卡，把这个放在传送平台上
Anka, deposit this on the transport platform,
这样普拉苏斯会知道
so Plasus will know
我们有更有价值的东西可以讨价还价
we have something more valuable to bargain with
比起我们的凿和镐
than our mortaes and thongs.
你很聪明，万娜，非常聪明
You are clever, Vanna, very clever.
搜索者很快就会来，米德罗
Searchers will be coming soon, Midro.
去其他矿井，告诉他们派驻哨兵
Go to other mines and tell them to post watchers.
他呢？
What of him?
我将确保他不会逃跑
I will see that he doesn't escape.
如果我们杀了他，就没有必要看守了
If we kill him, there will be no need to.
一个死的人质毫无价值，米德罗
A dead hostage is of no value, Midro.
只有特罗格莱特会知道
Only the Troglytes will know.
我带他来的
I brought him here.
我来决定做什么
I will say what is to be done.
你不是唯一的破坏者
You are not the only Disruptor.
我也可以决定
I, too, can say.
除了争吵，你还能做什么？
Can you do nothing but argue?
搜索者很快就会到这里
The searchers will be here soon.
@当安卡回来时，我们都会说
When Anka returns, we will all say.
这就是你在讨价还价的东西？
Is that what you're bargaining for?
杀死所有人的权利？
The right to kill everyone?
米德罗很幼稚
Midro is a child.
面具可以改变这种情况
The masks can change that.
回去挖你的矿，舰长
Return to the digging, Captain.
你打算让我在这里呆多久？
How long do you plan to keep me here,
当然前提是米德罗不杀我
providing Midro doesn't kill me of course.
直到我们在矿井里得到帮助
Until we have help in the mines
并在云城中有一席之地
and our homes are in the clouds.
那是相当长的时间
That's quite a while.
比我预期的要长
Longer than I expected.
我们被封在里面了
We're sealed in.
完全被封了
Completely.
但很快大气就会用完，我们会死的
But soon the atmosphere will go. We'll die.
死于看不见的东西？
Die from something that can't be seen?
你让我大吃一惊，万娜
You astound me, Vanna.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
企业号，请回答，柯克呼叫企业号
Enterprise, come in. Kirk to Enterprise.
企业号，请回答
Enterprise, come in.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
我是史波克
Spock here.
我们一直在试图联系你，舰长
We've been trying to make contact, Captain.
有什么问题吗？
Is anything wrong?
没有什么，史波克先生，你锁定我了吗？
Nothing, Mr. Spock. Are you locked in on me?
已锁定，准备传送货物
Locked in, and ready to beam up consignment.
情况有一点变化，史波克
Circumstances dictate a slight variation, Spock.
等待指示中
Standing by for instructions.
保存这些坐标
Hold on these coordinates.
定位高级顾问并立即将他传送到这些坐标来
Locate the high advisor and beam him to these coordinates immediately.
无需提前沟通，再说一遍
Without advance communication. Repeat.
无需提前沟通
Without advance communication.
听到了吗，史波克？
Have you got that, Spock?
指示明确
Instructions clear.
我会立即执行
I shall carry them out immediately.
通话完毕
Spock out.
你要把普拉苏斯也关进来？
You would seal Plasus here also?
目的是什么？
For what purpose?
我正在准备一场演示
I'm preparing a demonstration
关于没人相信的气体的影响
on the effects of unbelieved gas.
他说在没有警告的情况下把高级顾问传送下去？
Beam the high advisor down without warning, did he say?
那不是他的原话，斯科特先生
That's not an exact quote, Mr. Scott.
然而，意思没错
However, it does express the thought.
我要看看顾问的表情
I'd like to see the advisor's face.
你会有这个机会的
You will have that opportunity.
舰长说了立刻，是吗？
The captain did say immediately, did he not?
这是他的原话
Now, that is an exact quote,.
斯科特先生，我建议你亲自操作传送装置
Mr. Scott,  I suggest you handle the transporter yourself.
这可能非常微妙，对我们来说是传送问题
This could be very delicate as a problem in transporting for us
对舰长来说是外交问题
and in diplomacy for the captain.
是的
Aye.
有什么烦心事吗，卓克辛？
Something's upsetting you, Droxine.
没有，父亲
No, Father.
怎么了？和我说说
What is it? Tell me.
真的没有，我没有不高兴
No, really. I'm not upset.
我只是站在这里望着太空
I was just standing here looking into space
并想知道他是否会回来
and wondering whether or not he would return.
他永远不会回来，我已经看到了
He will never return. I've seen to that.
但是天顶石对他来说是如此重要
But the zenite is so important to him.
他必须拿到它
He must have it.
会交付的
It will be delivered.
哪怕我们得杀了下面的每个特罗格莱特，也会交付
If we have to kill every Troglyte below, it will be delivered.
到那时，可能为时已晚
By that time, it may be too late.
或许他确实有办法…
Perhaps he does have a method.
他什么都不懂
He knows nothing,
除了如何摧毁我们的权力和我们的社会
except how to destroy our power and our society.
我禁止你再说起柯克舰长，甚至是想到他
I forbid you ever to speak of Captain Kirk, or even to think of him.
[斯科特]]史波克先生的传送室
[SCOTT] Transporter room to Mr. Spock.
史波克来了
Spock here.
我已经锁定了云城议会画廊的坐标
I've locked into the coordinates of the cloud city council gallery.
准备传送高级顾问
Ready to transport the high advisor.
你得等一下啊
You'll have to delay.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
在画廊里探测到两个生命体
Picking up two life-forms in the gallery.
他们靠得非常近
They are inseparably close to one another.
我们无法只传送其中一个
We cannot transport one without the other.
你是不是说了“立即”一词是舰长的命令的原话？
Did you say the word "immediately" was an exact quote of the captain's orders?
的确如此，斯科特先生
Precisely, Mr. Scott.
那我们要照做吗？
Are we going to do anything about it?
等到高级顾问一个人或者能被分离前
Until the high advisor is alone or can be isolated,
舰长得要等着了
the captain will have to wait.
除非你有其他选择
Unless you have an alternative.
我会再考虑一下
I'll give it further thought.
我没有在想柯克舰长
I wasn't thinking of Captain Kirk.
是那个有着精致形状的耳朵的人
It's the one with those exquisitely-shaped ears.
他叫史波克
His name is Spock.
他是我在想的人
He's the one I was thinking about.
你知道他有令人难以置信的敏感听力吗？
Did you know that he has the most incredibly sensitive hearing?
为什么，我几乎相信
Why, I almost believe that
如果我站在这里呼唤他
if I stood here and called out to him,
他能听到我的邀请
he would hear my invitation to come
来和我们一起再参观一会儿
and visit with us for a little while longer.
哦，他并不比他的朋友好
Oh, he's no better than his friend.
我们试试？
Shall we try?
怎么了？
What is it?
破坏者万娜失踪了
The Disrupter Vanna has disappeared.
她的警卫被发现昏迷不醒
Her guard was found unconscious.
他被柯克舰长袭击了
He'd been attacked by Captain Kirk.
柯克舰长在哪里？
Where is Captain Kirk?
他不知道，长官
He did not know, sir.
直到我去帮助他，他才恢复了神智
He did not regain his senses until I came to his aid.
这就是他们用来说服我们的理由
This is the kind of reason they use to persuade us.
他们很绝望
They are desperate.
我不想再听到为他们的辩护了
I will hear no more defense of them.
我敢肯定史波克先生不会这么做
I'm sure Mr. Spock would not behave so.
马上离开这里
Leave here at once.
去听你的音乐
Go to your music.
父亲，我们是否对自己的方法如此肯定
Father, are we so sure of our methods
以至于我们从不质疑自己的所作所为？
that we never question what we do?
史波克到传送室
Spock to transporter room.
我是斯科特
Scott here.
锁定议会画廊坐标
Lock in on council gallery coordinates.
锁定，长官
Locked in, sir.
传送
Energize.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
传送中
Energizing.
怎么样，斯科特先生？
How are you doing, Mr. Scott?
很好，史波克先生
Fine, Mr. Spock.
高级顾问正在平台上实体化
The high advisor's materializing on the platform.
立刻把他传送给柯克舰长
Beam him down to Captain Kirk immediately.
正在传送，长官
Energizing, sir.
他正在去见舰长的路上
He's on his way to the captain.
干得好，斯科特先生
Good work, Mr. Scott.
顾问看起来相当生气
The advisor looked mighty angry.
我希望他不会给舰长带去太多的麻烦
I hope he doesn't give the captain too much trouble.
舰长会使用他惯用的外交手段
The captain will employ his usual diplomatic balm.
绑架星球官员是一项严重的罪行
Abduction of a planet official is a serious crime.
你会为此付出代价，我保证！
You will pay for this, I promise you!
除非你确信天顶石气体的影响，顾问先生
Not until you're convinced of the effects of the zenite gas, Mr. Advisor.
影响？我在这里已经快一个地球时了
Effects? I've been here nearly an hour of your Earth time,
你和万娜甚至更久！
you and Vanna even longer!
我看不出任何人有什么变化！
I see no changes in any of us!
也许你需要更近距离的接触
Perhaps you need closer exposure.
装满那个容器
Fill that container.
你是要我挖天顶石吗？
Are you suggesting that I dig zenite?
我坚持
I insist.
你确实会为此付出代价
You will indeed pay for this.
你也是，万娜
You, too, Vanna.
你也是！挖！
You, too! Dig!
[通讯器哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BLEEPS]
我是柯克，怎么了？
Kirk here. What is it?
通信确认，舰长
Contact check, captain.
距离上次与你通信已经超过一个小时了
It has been over an hour since your last communication.
你们的命令是待命
Your orders are to stand by.
现在，继续执行它们，通话完毕
Now, carry them out. Kirk out.
待命中，舰长
Standing by, Captain.
但是，让我提醒你，我们只剩五个小时来…
However, let me remind you, we have only five hours left to.
这很不像舰长
It is very unlike the captain.
会是天顶石在影响他吗？
Can the zenite be affecting him?
我变得昏昏欲睡
I grow faint.
氧气在消失
The oxygen is going.
她是对的，柯克，带我们离开这里
She's right. Kirk, transport us out of here.
我们会在气体生效后离开
We'll leave when the gas has effect.
它永远不会生效
It will never take effect.
带我们离开这里！
Transport us out of here!
挖！
Dig!
傻瓜，我们会死的！
Imbecile. We'll die!
我说挖！
I said dig!
我是整个星球的高级顾问
I am high advisor of all the planet.
我不会再听你的命令了！
I will take no more orders!
再走一步，我就杀了你
One more step and I'll kill you.
气体
The gas.
舰长，你说得对
Captain, you were right.
正在产生影响
It's taking effect.
舰长，你说得对
Captain, you were right.
你用凿和你用相位枪的时候一样勇敢吗？
Are you as brave with mortae as you are with a phaser?
这两个都能杀人
Both will kill.
企业号！企业号，帮助！
Enterprise! Enterprise, help!
企业号！
Enterprise!
企业号，我是史波克
Enterprise. Spock here.
他们会互相残杀，帮帮我们
They'll kill each other. Help us.
帮帮我们！
Help us!
企业号！企业号！
Enterprise! Enterprise!
天顶石气体影响了你，舰长！
The zenite gas has affected you. Captain!
天顶石气体！
The zenite gas!
天顶石气体
Zenite gas.
小心，吉姆！
Look out, Jim!
舰长！
Captain!
呃…
Well.
看来我的小示范…相当成功
it seems my little demonstration was. quite a success.
我不喜欢过滤器，甚至不喜欢面具
I don't like filters, or even masks.
我更喜欢“防护物”这个词，不是吗？
I like the word "protector" much better, don't you?
它不那么专业，因此，不那么准确
It is less technical, therefore, less accurate,
但也许对功能的描述更通俗
but perhaps more generally descriptive of the function.
看来你终究得到了你想要的东西
It appears you have what you came for after all.
舰长将得到他的天顶石，正如我所同意的那样
The captain will have his zenite just as I agreed.
同意？
Agreed?
特罗格莱特字典中没有这样的词
There's no such word in the Troglyte vocabulary.
舰长会拿到他的天顶石
The captain will have his zenite.
无需你的同意
No thanks to an agreement by you.
它必须通过武力获得
It had to be obtained by force.
因为这是我们能够获得应得的东西的唯一途径
Because it is the only way we can obtain what is due us.
对你的教育呢？
How about your education?
那也是强迫的吗？
Was that by force?
它符合你当时的目的
It served your purpose at the time.
你可以拥有这些过滤器，它们对你有好处
You could have had those filters for all the good it will do you.
他们会非常有效，长官
They will be very effective, sir.
它们已经过严格的测试
They've been severely tested.
特罗格莱特将不再遭受发育迟滞和情绪困难
And the Troglytes will no longer suffer from retardation and emotional difficulties.
他们都会像她一样…
They will all be like her.
忘恩负义，报复心强
ungrateful, vindictive.
是的，我们的要求才刚刚开始
Yes. Our demands have just begun.
这是天顶石，舰长
Here is the zenite, Captain.
就像我承诺的那样
Just as I promised.
谢谢你，万娜
Thank you, Vanna.
斯特拉托斯是如此令人愉快和美丽
Stratos is so pleasant and so beautiful.
我想我害怕离开它
I think I'm afraid to leave it.
下面的知识中存在着巨大的美
There is great beauty in the knowledge that lies below.
只有一种方式能真正体验它
And only one way to really experience it.
我会去矿井
I shall go to the mines.
我希望不再被限制在云端
I no longer wish to be limited to the clouds.
你的星球是这样的吗？
Is. your planet like this one?
不
No.
不，瓦肯完全不同
No, Vulcan is quite different.
哪天我应该去看看
Some day I should like to visit it.
也许某种形式的调解可以帮助你解决困难
Perhaps some form of mediation can be helpful in your difficulties.
联邦工业化局可能对你有所帮助
The Federation Bureau of Industrialization may be of aid to you.
我绝不允许任何干涉！
I will tolerate absolutely no interference!
只要我统治，你就不能踏足这里！
You will not set foot here as long as I rule!
相信我，长官，我既没有时间也没有渴望回到这里来
Believe me, sir, I have neither the time nor the desire to return here.
要不是得回答你对我的指控才不会回来
Only answering your charges against me will force me back.
我坚持这些指控
And I shall press them.
你犯了绑架罪，舰长！
You are guilty of abduction, Captain!
你犯了攻击星舰指挥官并谋害其生命的罪行！
You're guilty of attacking a starship commander and plotting against his life.
舰长，也许这两件事最好都忘掉
Captain, perhaps both incidents are best forgotten.
是的，万娜
Yes, Vanna.
它们从未发生过，顾问先生
They never happened, Mr. Advisor.
史波克先生，让我们去派送天顶石
Mr. Spock, let's get that zenite delivered.
我相信我们只剩3个小时了
I believe we only have three hours left.
准确地说是2小时59分钟，舰长
Two hours, 59 minutes to be exact, Captain.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
斯科特先生，把我们传送上去
Mr. Scott, beam us up.